Carl, can you hear me?
Yep.
How you doing?
Yourself. You good?
Just driving down to BYU right now.
I mean, we're from.
What's that?
We're from.
Saratoga Springs.
There you go.
Oh, so not like crazy far.
Yeah.
Is the meeting on yet?
Hey, he's going. Yep.
Sorry. Yeah, it's not.
How's it going?
Good, are you?
Great, I'm on my way, but I'll be digital until then.
Okay, yeah, all good.
Carl, thanks for joining.
How are you doing? Good, how about yourself?
Can't complain.
Okay.
Internship going okay for you, Carl.
Yeah, no, it's been really fun. It's been really good. I'll be up in Lehigh, so I'll just
be online the whole time. Yeah, yeah.
That makes
sense.
Thanks for
making the time
to
jump on still.
A number of times I've heard,
oh yeah, I talked to Xavier and then things made so much more sense. So,
I think we're doing.
Hey,
Audrey.
Good morning.
Good. It's
like, maybe just so that. We're weird. We're
twins. We can be too. That type we did? Yeah.
No, that. Typically,
we just say we're two to the park because we are. Huh? Did you ever like get that? Only on
the hike as a joke, so.
Like a lot of the line were felt.
What's funny is that the net IDs are so similar. For me, I'm just, like, it gets anything
like, like, no.
Same last name,
like three different
letters. Yeah, like, hey, Chris,
something, something. Um,
let's extend.
0,0,0, 3.
When I'm going to stand?
Yeah,
if it was over a year, if it was over a year, that was when we first started, totally that,
I was starting that man.
I think, yeah,
that's so funny.
It's so funny. It's so funny.
It's so pretty. That's like,
it's not a lot of it's hard. That's like one, I like a video. It's like we're sort of born
in the same place where the key need the part and beholding right. So, you know,
it's perfect.
Both I last name, but he said, okay. You know she spelled it wrong.
I don't know.
Well, tactic transcription and I've heard it, so.
That's recorded
now.
Yeah.
Let's get started.
Andrew, let me mind. Start us off the first off of.
Dearly Father, we're grateful for the same. We're grateful to meet together as a rap. So
I'm discussed by progression of different projects and how domestic continue
to progress and bless this with a spirit with knowledge and
this time as we do not have to see forward,
helping their work to help by
children. The name of Jesus Christ, you know. Thank you, thank
you, so. So
let's get
started. AI
discussion, lab culture. I asked Xavier the other day when we were meeting,
so is the lab culture falling apart?
And I think your response
was, well.
The voice was,
maybe, maybe that will.
I think you said, Well, not all of this.
So anyway, this topic is a bit on my mind a lot of just how we're using what is being
termed AI and general of AI in the lab.
What's the lab culture around it? And I think that this would be a good time to just
talk about what we want that to look
like in the lab,
what's gone well, what hasn't.
I've appreciated people's willingness to take the conversations
to GitHub,
which does
a couple things, it gives me some visibility on how AI is being used in the lab.
And maybe just kind of another point, even if Claude or co-pilot or any of these things didn't
exist, my hope and expectation would still be to have that kind of interaction on GitHub.
from kind of like this project management, like documentation perspective,
and Claude getting injected into that is kind of a nice convenience, and along with that
workflow too, like an extra benefit,
but like hopefully a little extra motivation to
kind of
keep going with the
GitHub, some of the GitHub things there.
There are
a
couple things I wanted to go through. One is I'm just going to screen share the,
that
GitHub discussion and everybody's responses so far. I'll just kind of read through those.
And then
we'll do some breakout discussions and then come back together. And
I will actually have us find isolated spots to go chat. And
I'm going to ask that one of you records it a video just because, videos
are easiest to put on YouTube.
So, like, just take a video to get the audio of the conversation, we'll come back, we'll
discuss, and just like to all of that. And those videos will get uploaded to the BYUvCL
channel. So I think I'm all kind of a discussion.
Sounds okay,
oops,
Davy? Yeah. Yeah, okay.
Sorry for thinking.
picking on you the
instigator
yeah and then online Audrey gauge Carl does that sound okay for you
guys who of the three of you who's able to
talk
like would would the three of you be able to have a conversation just online
I'm pulling up at BYU right now so I'll be in person just a minute oh that's right
that's right Audrey and Carl are you in Carl I think you said yes Audrey Are you in a position
where you could unmute and chat with Carl? Yeah,
I can talk.
Okay, cool, cool, sounds good.
Okay, so let me go ahead and do a screen share. Any questions
before we
jump in? Okay,
let me pull up that discussion.
So the link was in Slack, but you can also get to it. So we've got BYUVCL discussions and
those high level thoughts about use of the in the lab and to save my voice a little bit
if you were the one who posted it, if I could ask you to read it also.
So this is a space to journal our perception, oh, sorry, your folks online, let me actually
screen share.
So this is a space to journal our perceptions and observations of AI. Please include direct
links to the specific get-up comments that are being discussed. I'll go and read, read Tins.
So in
regards in using AI for CAD modeling, AI was used to make tips for the wireless color sensor.
And sorry,
these are the three questions we'll talk about. So kind of keep these in mind while we're
going through. Like an experience where use of AI has helped you learn something or has been
productive,
a time when it's felt uneasy, unproductive, or crippling. Maybe that's an extreme. word but
I
was
having trouble thinking of synonym. Then what kind of lab culture would you support establishing
any specifics?
So in regards to using, oh sorry, AI was used to make tips for the wireless color sensor.
I actually did a good job with making tips for my specific usage, but it lacked in creating
a part with a design that would be improved for ease of changing out the part. While we used
AI for the purpose of documentation, I think I would have been able to make a part and eventually
made a part that would fit our needs to be. more directly. I enjoy the process of thinking
and pondering over how to improve a design, and currently AI does not come close to my capacity
to ponder complex designs.
I think using AI as a tool to give a human some design suggestions is very helpful, but it
takes away from the researcher if they don't improve their ability to reason, create, and
learn from the process of thinking involved in the creative process. As shown here, AI's
ability to automate tasks and make simple decisions is amazing and give the researcher more
time to work on tasks that require higher level thinking. In this instance, AI was able to
run a test for me and collect data. This will be very helpful because it can run 24-7. And
then I'll see if this pulls up.
So Tim's on EtClaude, can you pick up, move, run the following Google Cloud code, post here
the results, and then return the enclosure to its housing. So I was giving it this
code here.
And thought took 42 minutes, picked it up, sensor test ran, went
down mid-cycle.
This was the one that you pointed out here.
Any thoughts before we jump on? We have, I think, five more at least to go through about
kind of similar length, but any, anything jump out to you?
Yeah.
I get added to this because I haven't come here on this meeting on this discussion, but similarly,
I think, and super, super helpful to me and just like giving up to speed and learning about
the mechanical experience of what I'm doing in my specific area. But when it comes to doing
complex things that's what
I'm kind of well sure.
Whereas I'm able to do it with it. And it takes, say, I'm for a iteration to get a simple
working 3D model, 1 hours of doing. I have just experienced is a very significant.
Yeah,
yeah. Was that by chance with the pipette? Yeah, I'm like, let's make a dummy pipette. And
then in the end, did you end up? I ended up
this one.
Yeah,
second here.
Save that for later a little bit.
Sorry,
you didn't know that I was going to do that. But it
was going to do that. Okay, yeah.
Then, Gage, let's come back to Gages, just because you said you're on your way, parking.
So you can be here.
Let's jump to Sam's.
Yeah, go.
A little bit of a dough that.
Sorry. How did this project? You know,
I think you got a product at the time. At the day, everybody's five. Even though
the signature of the only design
of the cell. Of
course, the area situation would be the engineers and the computer and that
look at the same nature of understanding. So, and pretty how you can't get
to six-seven to all the situation is where we probably
shouldn't rely
on it. It's never really good for a conditional. I have to
pull that up
real quick.
So this is from the Powder Doser Project where generative CAD was such a huge focus, especially
initially. And so lots of comments here and discussion.
There were some fun ones here. Let's see, we can find one.
At
least I remember there
being some
tough ones.
Okay, never mind. Sorry.
Yeah,
like YouTube, they're going to trench run, and what about the experience in.
So I think that's here. We see that
we can't like it down.
But also, if you need, the client shift,
obviously, it's really we have this approach to be like to use the
ads in the heart and the California particularly the skills that I can be able to do.
But this year is all just about here in time, you're going to study and a little business
down the world
for the world as to be able to have a lot of time. The language,
they're lacking
in existence of privacy. For example,
in a case of the university,
which isn't far away what you do, by comparison, and they're going to be there with fear.
It's been very much, and the various kinds of language. And then
in that calibration test
The same time, which is a fine The dispense of one gram of
power that you can find those in the order which you get a supernames you need to be in a
way now and
how to you try to
do it like right now it's
Okay, yeah, yeah, I got to check to it
right now. Okay, yeah,
yeah, I got to try it.
Yeah,
got to get new lab codes, though. So budget is a little tighter than what I
ordered this initially.
Working for
it. That's a very hard for the interesting as to background
tasks of faculty. The other aspects of it is very helpful for the potential process of
students series and even for the idea to make sense of course of the students and even for
I also think that no longer best students with experience with experience with experience.
agree.
Yeah, any form? into the next one any oh thanks
any
any any thoughts or things that come to mind I
think one thing that came
in mind doing
this again was
the
workflows that we have are different than indigenous standards whereas for research if somebody
asks you a question by your paper you're expected to
know everything about what we just research
like you are considered the expert
and if there's some portion of your research
that you're like oh i don't know I opted it to quad or whatever. In industry, they're
like, ah, yeah, that's fine. Like,
as long it's working, it's working. If you say
that to another researcher, they're going to be, like, why are you qualified?
Like, and the purpose of a master's or
a PhD or a bachelor is to show that you have a certain level of confidence in the game skills.
I was just
talking to my brother a month
ago, and he's talking about one of his co-workers in a national lab, and he's like,
I came out of my PhD with no workable skills.
Like
that
was just like how is PhD in
the development and
he was like fortunately
I was
able to get a job, but
you can come out of a whole education with no work
to still.
AI is
just a way that makes that
easier to happen than that's a big.
One of the reasons why I
will try
really hard to prevent myself from getting an e-bike anytime in the near
future is is that
and a second car for as long as we, as long as we can, is that I know
a
bike is the only mode of transportation I have from my house to work. And so I
take the 20, 25-minute bike ride each way, every day, except for occasional times when
it's raining
ash, for example.
And so, like,
if I had an e-bike, I know myself well enough that I would probably start relying on the
e-bike intensively rather than getting a workout that I need every day, kind of going back
and forth for the same day. Well, I can get there faster, and then also I don't like being
sweaty, like, it's distracting to me, and all these other things, and so it's so much easier
to be complacent when the tool is there. Whereas, like, some people will use e-bikes for
mountain biking, and they'll still get a really good workout. out of it and so there's kind
of a but they get less of some of the
kind
of tedious grueling parts of it they get a little more of the fun
part
so I
think some really good like the points
there
just
by fact of being there it's easier to become complacent
I
don't if you have any other thoughts of your
well this
is an education and that that should be the primary focus even as you enter graduate work
yeah Your advisor might not care so much about your education necessarily, but you should
be focused on yours.
Yes, yeah, I definitely took that approach for all of my degrees. If
I wasn't learning something,
if there wasn't a challenge, something challenging for me to kind of wrap my head around,
I wasn't interested, and I didn't really, like, I would still try to meet expectations, but
that also, cause some friction at times and overall I think things turned out pretty well
but that was really important to me so anyone in the lap feels like they're getting that
friction with me then I need to sit down and kind of reflect on my own actions and
love to kind of chat about that and so I really valued that as I was going through research
and I do not want to
set a culture where that gets taken away.
My question is that I don't know if this are open, like people as well as well. But it's
not like we can choose
to not buy
the e-bike.
Right? It's the, yeah, it's like the e-bike is there.
And like, oh,
sorry, I bought it, yeah, I bought it for almost. Like, I literally bought it for everybody.
And the question I ask is,
how important is it for us as students going into,
the professional world soon
to be competent in not only using AI but using the AI for where we
learn a lot from it and also we
get we
get effective results with AI and our own competency and and so just a little bit of okay
we do need to find this because it's not like we can just
say okay I'm not
going to get this I'm
not going to use this AI because it's there
and and so
that that I think it is a more thing to this And who
of us has driven to the gym before?
Yeah.
I was going to say with that, I think, you know, even though it's fictional, I think prime
examples like Tony Stark, who,
you
know, he knows all the math, he knows everything
that he needs to do.
But, you know, he uses
his AI Jarvis to also, you know, be his tool to, you know, be there to
run the tests that. he already worked out
or to support his reasoning
or
stuff like
that. So kind of
like that, where Jarvis is a support to
Tony Stark and not doing Tony Stark's work.
I guess I'm the guys with the idea that our education is super important. And I
think there's a good relationship. It relates a lot to how we've learned things in general,
like all through school. We taught how to do it. math and only after you understand how to
that then you get to calculate and do things for you, right? And the reason for that is,
I think it's powerful and helping us learn and understand and also build the ability to think.
I think it comes a point when,
like,
for example, some of these research papers we've been working on, it's all done by AI, and
I know the difference of myself, personally, like, when I write out whole paper, I really
understand everything that's going to do with is it for me that I'm going back, you know,
okay, what is this me? I don't know, there's so much going on here, but I think that happens
a lot of day, it has so much output, you're trying to go through, like, is this right, is
this right? There's so many
assumptions and the stuff that
is you can construct yourself, yeah,
there's a,
there's a sense of, like,
there's a vagueness to,
um,
you don't know what the conclusion they're coming from. Um,
and so like, from personally, I want to find a balance of
learning
the skills that I'm having it
to do for me,
and then
applying the added to it after that or with it. I still know where that balance sits, you
know,
because people
are going to write papers a lot faster than I will. If I don't use the ad, I'd write it,
the first draft, or whatever it is,
that's option. Yeah,
writing's been a pretty recurring theme. This might be a good... segue to,
you know, maybe jumping
to...
Yeah. Yeah. The
part I
mentioned another, I mean, it's kind of...
That's great. This is a good.
Ronnie, you had something, let's say, maybe jump in.
Oh, I guess...
...wee going to ask you
to learn and about that the user is offered. because
there's
a lot of things for my project that I don't understand.
So as in the project, probably understand the parts that I need to, instead of me having
to go through,
filter through all this information from either a text of that I bought or whatever other
still is that we find, if they just want to explain me and helps me not extended.
And then when I have,
um, I have, I is based up what it's taught me I can bounce my views off of it and then sometimes
I'm asking questions they've given me something wrong with it like
can be a false and
so
it's almost like a like a CA, a professor
or teacher
who has
been doing nice and because it can seek me what I need to know is how we have to go and find
things that able to talk to you online. I would just do the Google search now, but you're
at any means, and that's
someone to meet you.
And they really, it's nice to be able to,
how they, like, hold those in my ideas, and my opinion, what you're so you're getting, and
something like,
it's such a good.
I know,
yeah, yeah. This idea of,
and not the sense of the other, if you have different, and really assisting their robot,
like different things, and that you
get in the trouble is where it's doing extremely research, and research those roles, so having
a system to
be
AI is doing work.
That means if you stop there too,
like, yes. If you use
that because that's not your goal, like, I don't really care about blank, I want to get over
that so that I can focus on this part, but if you just, yeah,
yeah, but yes, if you have AI, like, do the research and write the paper about it, then we'd
be able to conference to present that paper, and it's like, you
know what that word means.
Yeah,
that's what you get into trouble and that's where we let it get broad things for us. As we
say,
yeah, treating it like a TA, okay,
I want to do this thing, how
we do this, I think, go forward,
especially if that context is
for the paper
for the communication or for the doing
more research later on. Yeah.
Could you have Gene Kwan record the presentation next week too? Yeah, you guys are. So Marcus
will be giving the first oral talk of the group at a conference, I think,
right? Am I?
Yeah, so.
The guinea pig.
Yeah, Marcus is the guinea pig.
So,
yeah,
and that's been a topic,
okay.
Let me make sure that you have the understanding that you need to be able to be able to.
And we'll see.
Time is, what I mean is, like,
the experimental timeline was delayed to the, you know, the unexpected delays that are, that
should always be expected. There will be unexpected to the point where it's, you might be
in the situation. Well, do I step back and take the time to dig into some of these things,
or do I try to get, finish up the experimental campaign so that we have the results to present
on? Like, you're probably in that, That's
a huge
back
and forth thing in the last few
weeks. It takes a lot of time to go through to troubleshoot the equipment, to read what AI
thinks is wrong. Half the time with equipment, it has no idea what's going to all the equipment.
And also to figure out, well, how is this experiment working? And what will the results mean
when we get them, all of that stuff? Yeah, it's been back and forth between those two coming
up to
it.
Constant out. Yeah,
so I'm good.
So maybe you've
got about 20. 20 minutes left. Let's,
I'd like to save some time for
discussion
of wills.
So I guess my invitation would be to go back to this thread and look at
some
of the other comments from people, add your own replies in if you
feel to.
Let's jump over to
this.
So we are going to break. So we are going to break out a little bit, you could maybe find,
it might be best to go out into the hall and just find those space where you can talk without
somebody else's conversation, right in your ear sort of thing.
But what's an experience where the use of AI has helped you learn in the lab or enhance productivity?
And if one of you could take a video,
about
five minutes. We'll come back. And then online, all mute.
So for those online, so Audrey and Carl,
I will, yeah,
just groups of, yeah, groups of two, oh, wait, do we have two? We have
six,
okay. No,
no, I'll be, I'll be discussing with
somebody's. Oh,
count me, count me. Yeah,
yeah, so we've got even, even numbers. I'm gonna,
oh, I just realized my audio output, sorry Audrey and Carl, if you said something, I may
have had that muted accidentally.
Can you hear it snobger?
I'm so sorry, yes. There's a button on my laptop that mutes, and
I think I accidentally clicked it. I don't know
if Carl was saying anything, but I was just finishing typing up my essay that
I wrote.
Awesome, awesome. I think I saw that I got those there just now. Oh, yeah.
It's so long. I didn't realize how long it was getting.
I'll get the audio here muted, and then I'll turn it back on after we all kind of come back
to the other.
Like on my, on my computer, so it's not. Yeah. Okay. And then that way you guys can just
chat.
That was actually not the case. Apparently pushing that button doesn't mute. everything.
It's yeah like
an experience where it's helped you learn like a positive experience something that
you should just give me like a quick rundown on what you just did because I have not already
yeah
okay
we're all going out
you guys will get
the room to yourself to just chat for the entire
space. So
I
can't mute audio.
Andrew, you're still on me.
sorry about that.
You can zoom calls me. Okay,
I kind of talked about how
using it from model generation feels a little limiting because we can't directly edit those
models. you could pull them into on shape and you could add a little bit to them, but
it doesn't work very well.
Sorry, I feel like a little echo,
right?
You are, Sterling left this computer on. Oh. No worries, though.
And then I agree with these points that it doesn't feel like our skills
are being utilized very well, with this model generation, it would be way easier to just
make configurations on one cat model rather than having AI generate everything, having
to tune every little structure that are curious.
And if you're making those models, you don't get to know those models as well, which means
it is harder to fix them if they're having issues or sometimes they have geometry errors,
the mess of things that if a human had made them, you know, would have been fine, because
we wouldn't have done that right off the bat.
Yeah,
I'm really
worried about the real things where we've got a lot of AI generate a lot of what we're
writing to the point where, like, I spent a lot of time writing my abstract, and we ended
up feeding it through AI, added a bunch of sources and like me afterward and I didn't really
that was the way to go. I think that we should have read those sources.
And yeah, that's about the helpful is that it can teach you things and
I think that's
the
best use of me as a resource. And so it was really helpful for debugging
a 16 3D printer for me.
But I
feel like it I feel like we're pushing other areas.
And
I think AI has been super good as like, I've been thinking of it as like an assistant
in a lot of ways where like I use AI a con for the lab and then for like my work and stuff.
Just to like help myself stay organized,
I have found that super useful.
I've also found it super useful to, like, be able to, like, write code and stuff with it,
but when doing that, I think it's essential to, like, go back and actually understand what
the code is doing. So, like, I'll use AI and generate a ton of code,
and then I'll go back through all of it and figure out what the heck it just did and what
I want to change or what I need to optimize. Because it doesn't usually get it quite right.
It might make it function, but it won't quite work exactly like I want or need it to. So
I found that super interesting. I think the biggest thing is just recognizing that we're
going to have AI forever. Like, there's no getting away from any of that. We really need
to find a way to harness the power that it has to make us more, like, effective and
efficient.
If you don't know how to use it, you're going to fall behind. That being said, if that's
all you use, you're useless because anyone can use AI. Right.
That's kind of my thoughts. I don't know. As far as using it in the lab, I guess I don't
know. Like, I use it a lot in the lab to, like, research stuff, just because it seems to
do, it's a really quick way to, like, compare stuff that takes a lot of the grunt work out
of it.
Yeah, and it's kind of finding information really fast,
too. Like, when I ask it to compare a mass amount of 3D metal printers, like, it's really
good at going to websites and pulling data and giving me a table that displays most results.
And that saves me a ton of time, right? I don't have to go track down all that information.
Like, it's just giving to me. And it's right. You know, I mean, it's accurate. It pulled
that from their site.
When I ask AI to do other things, sometimes it'll, like, just completely hallucinate. When
I ask it for, like, how can I build this equation to optimize this process? It has no idea.
And so it'll just spit something random. And if I run with it, like, I'm an idiot for trusting
it completely and not trying to verify what it's doing. Yeah,
I agree with that, especially with finding sources. I think it's important to go and read
through those ourselves, or at least skin, you know, make sure that we're talking about the
right things.
Yeah,
and like, just from, like, my short internship work experience that I've seen, it's, it's
everywhere. Like, literally half of my day is working with AI to optimize a process.
Oh, are you in internship right now?
Yeah, I am.
Oh, Max, what are you doing?
Like, structural engineering stuff. Cool.
So, not quite mechanical, but close enough, and it's a work experience. But I found it so,
yeah, and I found it just so interesting, like, how often they use Gemmonin and Klaug
and all these things. Like, they are into it really deep. And so a lot of, like, my internship
has been, like, finding the limits of AI. for them and then saying, hey, this is as far as
we can push this.
Like, lots of their tools are using AI to verify human work. And in the process, like, they
will be able to really
cut
down in, like, the amount of man-hours and manpower that they need to do stuff because AIs
are so effective at doing what I call the grant work.
And so I think that's super interesting to see it. It's like, this isn't going anywhere.
Any business that's like wants to be strong is going to use this and then have someone verify
it.
So I think it's really interesting to see what the world will become because all of a sudden
you're, I don't know, I think it's really interesting. You just have to verify. You verify
your sources, verify the work, verify the equations.
And once you kind of do that, like, it's the math, it usually does pretty well on. Especially
where like a lot of the stuff I'm working with is kind of, of like our material, not material
science, but mechanics and materials class. And so I think this applies to the lab to it.
It does a lot of like easy grunt work very quickly and effectively. It just can't be allowed
to make like core decisions or like core tat or else it'll just belly flop.
Yeah, I agree with that.
And part of it is figuring
out that was a rant
grunt work that it can manage too, right? Like, I mean, we've spent months trying to get
it to work with the CAD models, and it's just not doing very well, and I
think
that's okay, because I think plenty of us actually enjoy doing CAD, you know?
And every CAD model is going to be different. It wouldn't be, like, recording data and sorting
it and stuff. Like, that's something that AI would be amazing for.
But, yeah,
it's a little,
yeah. That's one of the limits I think that AI has is it's not very good at generating those
structures that we need.
Generating images and like spatial awareness AI is very poor at. It does really well with
like analyzing information and like things to do with like words and things like that. It
goes very good at image analysis, spatial analysis, things like that. It's not there.
Yeah, it doesn't live in the 3D world with us. It's all just code and stuff. And it can be
super helpful for code. I mean, I've been a little more careful with generating so much
code at once because often it'll come up with, like, a function or something that I haven't
ever used before, and I'll be like, hey, what's that? And then it takes a little more time,
but then you're still learning with it, but often it can feel a little like you're trying
to catch up to where AI is at, and you're never going to get to that point. but you
learn
a lot,
but I think it's ultimately better writing my own code because then I know exactly how
it works and how I want it to be working.
That's my opinion. If you
have one of the subs.
We might,
I think we'll jump
back together to,
yeah, let's jump to the next question.
So let's just kind of shift it over to lab culture. So like in the vertical cloud
lab at BYU specifically,
what kind of things could we do? Like, what kind of conversations could we have to help out?
Like, what kind of lab culture do we want? How do we set that kind of culture here? Especially
as new people come in, as people graduate and then pass off the baton, you know, what
is the lab culture? like that
so regarding AI or just general
AI
yeah and then I think it would be good to in future what's
a breakoff talk for me.
We'll do break off yeah another break off in the side.
Yeah, yeah, and we're
going too.
Sorry,
you guys can keep going. Sorry,
you guys can keep going. What do you think, Audrey?
I
don't know, I'm bad, I use AI a lot, like a lot, a lot, a lot.
As far as like the culture of it, I think that's very personal. I know, like, Xavier doesn't
use it very much at all.
Yeah.
I mean, do you still feel like you're learning and that you're capable when you're using
it, though?
Yes and no.
Yes and no. There are times, kind of like what you're saying at the end, I literally will
chase AI through, like, tons of code trying to figure out how it's doing, what it's doing.
I mean, at the end of the day, I come back to it and kind of just, like, look at it, And
it's like, well, it's working. I have a kind of a grasp of what I think it's doing. Oh, it's
doing it. I don't know how that function exactly works. Like, I really don't know.
But it works. And I think I know kind of what it's doing. Could I, like, teach someone else
what it's doing? No. Yeah. And so I guess I trust it maybe too much in
that sense.
That being sad,
like,
for me, it's kind of, of like the means to the end on like certain things. Like I would prefer
not to be coding stuff my whole life and so that's not something that entreats me. And so
maybe I'm short circuit, like short-circuiting my education in that aspect. But at the same
time,
it's something that I don't hope to be doing my whole life.
Gotcha. So you're not worried about your coding skills. Yeah. So like, you don't see yourself
using them very much.
Like long term, yeah, I'm not as worried about that. where I do spend, like, a lot more time
understanding is things with, like, the 3D printers and, like, material science stuff. Like,
that's just information that I need to know, like, forever. And so, like,
when it comes to those things and I'm using AI, like, even right now, like, the amount of
times I say, okay, walk me through and teach me what you just did.
And it
will take, I will spend a ton of time going down that wormhole,
but I think it's still valuable. and I think it helps me not short circuit the educational
experience.
I think for me I'm using AI mostly as like a way to get out of things that I don't really
want to spend a lot of time on. That makes sense, and I don't particularly see myself as
like using them down the road.
Yeah, I think that's useful. I've definitely had semesters where I feel I'd maybe too much
on AI, and that wasn't helpful for me, for my... learning, so I'm definitely a
little more like, use it as little as possible, but like for things it can easily automate,
that's so, so beneficial. I just, I think we're on two opposite episodes of the spectrum
right now where you're relying on it like a lot right now, and I'm like, I don't want to
touch this
stuff, but. Yeah,
and it's been hard, because my internship, honestly, I thought it would be, like, showing
me that, like, I need to not use AI as much, and then, like, I got here and I don't know
if you're familiar with, like, Gemini notebooks and, like, Gemma, and, like, all of those
new features.
I spent, I spent probably a quarter to a half of my day, every day, using those tools
and either trying to break them, trying to make them work quicker, or trying to find ways
to, like, share them on, like, a larger scale. Like, that's all I'm doing. And then, like,
of course, going through as they work to, like, make sure they did the math right and they
have the equations, right?
You know what I mean, that, like, their reasoning isn't flawed, but I don't think I've had,
I can, I mean, I've been here since May. I can count on one hand. I think the times the AI
has gotten, like, the equation wrong for something, like, engineering related in
the sense that, like, it performed a calculation that was just false, or it was just wrong.
You know what I mean? Like, maybe four times. Yeah.
and so
just me knowing how to do it those four times was incredibly helpful but I think what it
really has done is like really lowered the barrier to entry of like going in and deep diving
into like specific things
I don't know
okay yeah no I can see that as
far as like the culture though like I think there has to be a balance like we have to use
it we can't say hey we're not going to touch that that being said I'm probably overusing
it for the extent where like probably
underusing it. So we just
need to...
You've got to find the balance where you use it, but you understand how you're using it and
what it's doing. We're like, I'm, yeah, I'm definitely in this sense where, like, sometimes
I don't understand everything of why it's happening. It just kind of does, and I just kind
of accept that, like, it has done its job well and move on, especially for, like, coding
things. When I plus run, and it runs, and it works like it's supposed to, I don't ask a ton
of questions. and just if I, and once I kind of like understand it a little bit, because
I just don't,
it's interesting, very interesting. When it comes back to, like, school, like, I feel like
how I always use the AI is, like a better way where, like, I use it a lot to, like, study
for things, but not necessarily to solve the exact problems I was solving, but maybe to solve
other problems. It makes any sense, like, just create additional problems. So you can see
the
workflow so that you can go do your own.
Yeah, but it was also very interesting in my thermodynamics class, the teacher really encouraged
AI research, although he's no longer teaching here.
Who was the teacher?
I forgot. He was an older,
bald man.
Okay, so it wasn't Magelby then, right?
No, thermodynamics was it wasn't Magelby, and it wasn't Dylan. It was someone else.
I'd recommend taking it from Dr. Dylan.
I already took it, but thank you.
Who did you take it with?
I took it with Dylan.
Did you? Okay, yeah.
I didn't like mine in the class, but it was a very interesting perspective on using AI to
learn.
Yeah, where are you actually at in the program right now? Because I'm starting capstone,
but it seems like I just took thermos, so.
I've got two more years still. Okay. I'm trying to do the program in four years, and so
I've got two more.
Like, this is the semester I'm taking like manufacturing and mechatronet. things
like
that. Manufacturing is awesome. Mechatronics,
it can be awesome. You're not allowed to use AIMA to watch out.
yeah,
but it can be so rewarding when something works and when it doesn't work, it's like,
oh,
interesting class.
Manufacturing is so much fun, though.
What else were you in?
Oh, I don't know offhand, but, you don't know. the writing class.
Yeah, that one's just a work.
Is it fun or is it just kind of busy work? Well, like
parts of it are fun. I mean, assuming every class has the same kind of flow, like the first
project is like, you're going to write a set of instructions for someone and you need to
make it really pretty easy to follow and stuff like that. And that's actually fun. And then
you have like your assortment of papers that you have to do that are less fun. But you get
you get to do. them done and it's right
though yeah I feel like that's a good use of AI to like use it to write instructions like
give it a bunch of data and processes and then have it write the instructions and then just
verify that it was good
I don't know okay
maybe not I mean
you also have to everything you submit you have to say what you used AI for and stuff like
that so just make sure whatever you use it for you're comfortable declaring to the professor
Or yeah, if you guys could take a second.
Yeah,
like we can, as long
as it's uploaded,
then, yeah, we can get everything.
And then, Audrey and Curl, you get, you get off easy because it's already, you know, recorded
and stuff. So now I need to do the upload to the channel.
Yeah,
I've been putting...
discussion between Ben Whitney and Sterling Baird about AI, like lab culture,
AI. Mostly the AI experience in between and Monk.
Yeah, yeah.
That does sound like a, that's a great podcast, the podcast episode.
Hey,
we about to get YouTube famous.
Yeah, with the amount of content, yeah.
Alright, so we get a thousand bikes on this. We're changing our time.
I've been putting these ones as public.
I gotta make it public. You get my idea. But then we
know what our
future career is if
we get some random person on our
YouTube channels,
be like, what is
it? What is it?
Okay.
Why did you do recommend me? I take
it no one had a hard stop at 11 other ways you probably would have gone to. I won't go too
much over, but I think just kind of coming back together,
action items, specific suggestions people had or thought of, then we can take things a little
bit more asynchronously afterwards, like,
can we filter down those suggestions, kind of pick a few things that we that we focus on
in the lab to kind of... We can use the transcript
to
compile them. That's what I will do after the session. Probably,
I build a charter and sign.
That would be an example of a specific suggestion, so thank you for offering
the
you know,
the second one after.
Yeah,
we could also have the goal to have one lab meeting where we don't use the word AI a single
time.
But yeah, one that came from struggling. What?
For most of them, you know,
it's probably. They're
more like highest, highest speaker has great donuts. Yeah,
yeah, I would probably be bringing donuts every week.
That's okay.
Just give the multiple shit.
Donuts are in third.
Audrey and Carl, did you guys want to start off with anything?
Like,
they kind of stuck out?
We just talked
about having balance. and making sure that we were using AI for like good things and just
kind of talk about where we personally were with using AI and how we can use it better in
the lab and kind of set that culture, I think.
Sounds good.
Yeah, agreed on balance. There was
a... Sorry,
I'm just wondering, would it be helpful? Like, when new people come into the lab, we would
run them through, hey, this is good ways to be using AI, like using it to teach you to do.
do things and using it to maybe like debug stuff and like I mean just
like things that are helpful you know things that are
borderline
I don't know if this is right or not maybe
like we
need some kind of like a tutorial to show people I guess
yeah
I like that Audrey that gets me thinking we can probably pull this some of the things from
this discussion and when I am doing onboarding with people. You guys all kind of know I sent
out a few links of videos to watch. I think I can add, probably add this in with one of those
kind of like onboarding things. Like,
yeah. Or maybe I missed heard Audrey, but I think I heard her say real.
So like, you know, we could make like a real of
us like being, this is
good. This is bad.
Yeah, so some, yeah.
So yeah, I think some examples would be really good. Yeah,
we'll go a few more minutes.
with folks yeah there are specific
thoughts or suggestions. I think just what we were talking about earlier, like, as an assistant
and
like,
treating it as,
I don't know if it's clear
the right word,
but, um,
are you, yeah, it's cool,
like, can help you refine your, like something like you might help talk is that instead of
saying, create this, we give it specific ideas, and then how they define out our
ideas, in
four-sustness make for more and so let me do all the
thinking. Yeah, yeah, the level of understanding some was talking about, so like, okay, this
was our idea which you understand why the competition funds this idea.
AI is just helping us get
rid of maybe some of the time we would have lost if part of our idea wasn't
even going to have read any fruit for that wasn't going to enter the profit. Like they will
just get rid of the time wasting. stuff, I guess.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Zeta.
Something Sam and I talked about was
making
a bigger commitment to reading recent relevant research paper.
Something that's been useful for me is, and this point should be because of the nature of
my research, it's like reading a few papers and I'm implementing them into these, you
know, I'm coding them or adjusting them for our specific research. So I read them, I like,
look at the code, and I'm like, okay, I think I need to do this, and I'm like, wait, this
does make sense, and then I read them again, and I'm like, oh, I didn't read this closely
enough, okay, this makes sense, and then I can go back and I have a better understanding
and back and forth, and
that has
helped me understand exactly what then I know the code is doing, and it
avoids me having, like a, if I can read that paper, that means I, can understand all
the things that are relevant to it. And then I avoid having just a summary education of the
topic, which is currently how we use AI, is, oh, this is, give me
the Spark Notes version. And so then you get a Spark's Notes education of that.
But then you read another paper that would still be expected to understand, but because you
only have a Sparks Note version of that, you don't know the details, you read a paper that's
related and then you don't understand that again and so you ask for a spark note's education
of that and so you miss out on having a good quality education of the topic broadly
so then you can read many research papers and to be able to explain it to other people more
effective.
I think
lab culture involving
reading
the source manuscript material and
I
don't know how you'd feel about this but maybe like spend time with the manuscripts, maybe
say it's still okay if you're like pinging flawed to help with things, but while you're waiting,
it's like keep reading, you know, try to,
yeah, but like have the PDF of the manuscripts that you're like the really core manuscripts
that
you want to understand in
front of you.
As an anecdote for finishing my last math paper, we are on this last part of the group and
the way that we had thought we were going to do it. ended up not working, you could figure
it out. And so I just, there were three types of theorems that I was like, if you have anything
related to these type of results, I need these. And so I had Claude, shirts them up, and
it gave me, like, five for each type. And then I just, I clicked through the, and I read
them. And I was like, oh, I found it. Yeah. Like, this theorem, as it was published, was
able to work. And then we were able to make a proof off of that.
rather than if I just said, okay, search and give me the results of these papers, it probably
would not have, I would actually bet that it would not have found it, but because I was able
to go through and read through these. Like, it is really good at finding relevant papers,
but giving them out, it probably doesn't do as well as a job.
Like, summarizing.
So in a similar way, like this, this idea of summary is dangerous with that.
If I do research and have AI writing, the science language, and get a paper, somebody takes
that paper and
summarize it out of science, you know,
it's like, why are we taking all these steps? You can be able to read the stuff and get right
there, right?
both the writing has been processed.
And if
we let
AI
is talking to different AIs, I'm talking with different AIs about research, then that's a
self-directing
that's not between the research.
And why we
have to
also the autonomy to stuff that we don't.
So that
we can make the papers and write the papers and use the difference in this. Yeah,
thanks everybody for
joining
the discussion and we'll get
the good. Please make sure you get the videos uploaded and then the last
two
minutes. Does everybody have Slack? Can they get Slack open pretty quickly?
I would like you to
so this is in the social channel
name
a couple animals for me just
tiger
lion zebra elephant
okay we
might only need
four
okay
was
that
August 5th
one more animal
thank you
we're going to wait for man's good yeah
So if you could put your
availability in here,
that would be much
appreciated.
I think
it's like to work today.
Let me. If you do
you want us to include
those?
Yeah, multiple times, just trying to find the one that works for everybody.
Yeah, you can.
So fourth.
Okay, thanks. Yeah, no bad.
Oh,
sorry, Ronnie, if you could, yeah, just, oh, no, that's good.
Oh, meant to do an ad channel for that.
Wow, that's a lot of zebras.
Oh, and crocodust.
Okay, cool.
Okay, we'll probably call it good there. Thanks, Audrey, Carl. Thanks, everybody.
A little break.